Key Benchmarks for the Healthcare Industry
Welcome back to this session on benchmarking. Some time ago,
I did an extensive research in the healthcare industry.
Looking at a lot of different types
of potential defect categories.
Into here. For example, here is ICU error rate, per day, per patient.
For example, ICU error rate, per day, per patient.
Showing about a DPMO of 10,000.
Which converts to 3.83 Sigma.
Let's take another one. Adverse drug events
of medication errors that resulted in death.
58,200 PPM, or about Three Sigma. Wow.
That's a scary thought. Here's a good one.
Hospital negligence about 10,000 PPM or about 3.83 Sigma.
Wow. As we start to look at all of these different types,
we can put those on to a benchmark chart like we've looked at before.
We’re going to pan. There we go.
Over here, we've got parts per million,
which is the same thing as defects per million opportunities.
A hundred, a thousand,
10,000 at that level, and so on, up to 100,000, up to a million.
Way up there at the top of the chart. Here's the corresponding Sigma. One Sigma,
two, three, four, five, and six.
And there is the transfer line, right there.
Now, let’s take a look at some of these.
Look at this. Surgical complications running about Three Sigma.
Drug injuries, about Two Sigma.
So your odds with a drug injury,
is about the same as your odds with Internal Revenue Service tax advice, about Two Sigma.
Let’s look over here. Injuries due to negligence. That's a good one.
Right there. About Four Sigma. Prescription errors.
Now look at this one down here. Anesthesiology. Anesthesia errors,
about Six Sigma. That's amazing.
Why can't they have anesthesiologists, start prescribing drugs?
Medical misdiagnosis of depression.
That's about One Sigma. Oh my. But, you can see overall the average
from this set of many, many different data points from the medical industry,
is all in that region of about Four Sigma.
With an industry median at about 3.4 Sigma.
Well, we know automobiles is about Four Sigma. Healthcare is about 3.4.
That would tend to say, as a society, we value the quality of our cars
more than we do ourselves.
That’s very, very interesting isn’t it? Well again, benchmarking is another way to bring this out.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.